<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning on Ru-Lai&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://ru-lai.github.io/tags/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learning on Ru-Lai&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 12:51:48 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ru-lai.github.io/tags/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Provide True Support</title>
      <link>https://ru-lai.github.io/2019/providetruesupport/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 12:51:48 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ru-lai.github.io/2019/providetruesupport/</guid>
      <description>Behind all great individuals is a core group of people who support them. These people help lobby for their goals and enable them to accomplish more than they thought possible. Recently, while on a Christmas road trip to see my parents, my intermittent fascination with the fighting game community (FGC) led me to stumble upon an interview showcasing true support. The title character is a personality in the FGC named Mike Ross.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning on the job</title>
      <link>https://ru-lai.github.io/2018/learningonthejob/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 12:51:48 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ru-lai.github.io/2018/learningonthejob/</guid>
      <description>The learner&#39;s work desk  One of the most rewarding (and challenging) things you can do as a developer is to implement something you’ve never done before.
It’s even harder to is implement something you have never done before while on a deadline. The pressure of needing to get work done in a specific time frame can add more stress to the already difficult challenge of finding an optimal solution to a new problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Spaced Repetition Changed My Life</title>
      <link>https://ru-lai.github.io/2017/spacedrepetitionchangedlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 12:51:48 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ru-lai.github.io/2017/spacedrepetitionchangedlife/</guid>
      <description>The Beginning   I didn’t start out in this world happy.
When I was young I felt different from most people. I would check out mentally at school, not want to play with friends, and spend a lot of my time watching TV and wishing I was someone else.
Most of my distress early on resulted from my mother’s passing away when I was four-and-a-half. Two years later more was added on when my father chose to remarry a physically and emotionally abusive woman.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>